我们将通过 Docker CLI 中的一些功能，以便我们能够
We're just gonna go through a bunch of the
features in the Docker CLI, so that we can
能为你做的各种事情都能做得好
just kind of type out and see all
the various things that it can do for you.
这是瑞士军队的一把刀对你做了很多事情
It's a Swiss army knife,
it does many things for you.
所以我只想让你熟悉一些其他的特点
So I just want you to be familiar
with some of the other features, so
当你去用它们的时候你可以在这里
that when you go to use them,
that you can have them here.
所以我们回到我的容器
So let's come back here to my container,
或是给我的终端
or to my terminal, rather.
首先我要说的是码头的拉力
First thing I'm gonna say is docker pull,
我要做 jturpin/好莱坞
and I'm gonna do jturpin/hollywood.
所以你可以看到，默认情况下，它已经是使用了最新的，对，
So you can see there, by default,
it was already using latest, right,
因为我没有指定一个版本但它会告诉你
because I didn't specify a version,
but it tells you that.
我已经下载了这个
And I already had this downloaded.
所以它就已经存在了，已经存在了，已经存在了。
So it's just going to say already exists,
already exists, already exists.
这样就能把它从注册表中提取出去
And so that will actually go and
fetch it from the registry,
所以它是本地缓存在我的电脑上的
so it's locally cached on my computer.
所以当我开始使用它的时候，它已经在那里了。
So later when I go to use it,
it's already there.
对吧 ?
Right?
我有很多人在课开始前做的，就这样
I had many of you do this before
the class started, just so
你会把这些都准备好的
that you would have these all ready to go.
既然已经在这里了我可以说码头上
And now that it's already here,
I could say docker run -it jturpin,
实际上我要用一个不同的容器来
and actually I'm gonna do this to
with a different container just so,
或者另一个终端是快速的。
or a different terminal real quick.
这是小文本，但你不用真正在乎它的意思。
This is small text, but you don't
have to really care what it's saying.
docker run-it， jturpin/holwood，然后我又要把宝莱坞放了
docker run-it, jturpin/hollywood, and
then I'm gonna put hollywood again.
这事对我来说太搞笑了
So, what this is doing,
this is hilarious to me.
这事什么都没做
[LAUGH] It's not doing anything.
> > [LAUGH] >> 但是，
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH]
&gt;&gt; But,
它应该看起来像好莱坞黑客的控制台
it's supposed to look like
a Hollywood hacker's console.
对吧 ?
Right?
所以有一个写这个的人说她会上飞机
So, one of the people that wrote this
said that she'll get on an airplane and
来看看是谁在她周围紧张
just run this,
just to see who looks nervous around her.
> > [LAUGH] > >
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH]
&gt;&gt; And
她会像这样把键盘敲起来
she'll just pound the keyboard like this.
是的，这就是这个容器的内容。
So yeah,
that's exactly what this container is.
我觉得它用的是 tmux ，对。
I think it uses tmux, right.
你可以在这里看到，就像在上面做矩阵一样。
You can see here,
it's like doing the matrix on the top.
然后它就会重新分说一切都是怎么安排的
And then it'll just re-split
how everything is set up.
那个正在做 SSH 密钥的
That one doing SSH keys.
真好笑
That's funny.
就像个小把戏对吧
So, it's like a trick, right?
但这是个有趣的派对把戏
But this is a fun party trick.
这绝对没有什么
This does absolutely nothing.
但看起来很吓人吧
But it looks really scary, right?
你可以看到有些甚至不起作用
You can see some of these don't even work.
但这对我们的
But does that make sense for
就像把东西从注册表中拉出来一样
like pull right where it pulls
something down off the registry?
如你想象的，我可以去 dockerhub.com
And as you might imagine,
I could go to dockerhub.com or
hub.docker.com/jturpin/hollywood, 和
hub.docker.com/jturpin/hollywood, and
我会在码头的轮毂上看到这个特殊的入口，对。
I would see that particular
entry in the docker hub, right.
所有这些点都与我的
Do all those dots connect with how I.
基本上，就像 VM 安装一样。
&gt;&gt; It's like a VM install, basically.
>> 就像 NPM，高速缓存，基本上， cutz 还没有实际运行，但是
&gt;&gt; It's like NPM, cache, basically, cuz
you're not actually running it yet, but
你要把它拉上来
you're pulling it in.
嗯。 好的。
Yeah.
Okay.
别这样了太荒谬了
Let's stop that, cuz that's ridiculous.
别说了别说了
Stop it, stop it.
谢谢。
Thank you.
好了我们再去另一个
Okay, now we'll go back to the other one.
那我们现在就做码头检查吧
So, let's do docker inspect now.
所以我要说码头检查
So, I'm gonna say docker inspect.
让我们做一个 12 点的节点。
And let's do node 12-stretch.
所以，你可以在这里看到，它输出了很多关于这个的信息。
So, you can see here, it just outputs
a lot of information about that.
它会给你哈沙它会给你标签
It'll give you the hash,
it'll give you the tags.
它会给你很多信息
It will give you a bunch of information,
它会给你环境变量
here it will give you
environmental variables.
就像你能看到的这里是 Node我不知道这跟 Yarn是一起的
Like you can see here, this came with
Node, I didn't know this came with Yarn,
但你可以看到它有一个 Yarn 版本
but you can see there that
it came with a Yarn version.
它会告诉你它将运行什么命令。
It'll tell you what command
it is going to run.
因此，每当运行节点时，它就会运行这样的节点。
So it actually runs node like
that whenever you run it.
入口点。
Entry Point.
你看它只会给你一堆这样的东西
See, it just gives you
a bunch of stuff like that.
因此，如果您想了解此版本的错误，那么这很有用。
So this is useful if you're like trying to
figure out what's wrong with this version
就像它是怎么建造的或者类似的东西
or like how was it built or
something like that.
像那样的东西
Bunch of stuff like that.
接下来我们要学习的是停手
Next one we'll learn is docker pause.
所以我要做 Docker run -dit。
So I'm going to do Docker run -dit.
因此破折号 d 是分开的，我们之前看到过。
So the dash d is detached,
which we saw previously.
我要再做一次 jturpin 的
I'm gonna do the jturpin
hollywood one again.
好莱坞但是现在这个是在后台运行的，对，
Hollywood, but then now this is
gonna run in the background, right,
我是说它在做些什么但我们没在看它对吧
which is, I mean, it's doing something,
but we're not watching it, right?
但你可以看到它还在运转
But you can see here it's still running.
我们可以看到它还在运行，但是这个在运行。
That we can see that's still running,
but this one here's running.
这一点很难理解。
And this is hard to read like this.
所以，就在第二个方面，我只是在缩小，这样你就可以在一行上看到这些。
So just for a second, I'm just zooming
out so you can see all these on one line.
你可以看到这里的状况，它已经上升了大约 7 秒钟。
You can see the status here,
it's been up for about seven seconds.
再一次，它已经上升了 7 秒。
So again, it's been up for seven seconds.
所以现在我可以说停手了
So now I can say docker pause, and
我就用那个集装箱的标识把它贴在那儿
I'll just take that container ID and
paste it right there.
现在如果我再说 " docker ps " 的话
And now if I say docker ps again,
它会说已经暂停了对吧
it's gonna say it's paused right there,
right?
不管它在做什么它只冻结了所有过程树
Whatever it was doing, it just
froze all of its process trees, and
它就停在铁轨上了
it's just stopping dead in its tracks.
现在如果我说停停的话就像你想象的一样
And now if I say docker unpause,
as you might imagine,
说 Docker ps 它又要执行了
say docker ps, it's back to execute.
那么另外一件事，如果你想暂停一些正在发生的事情，
So, another thing, if you want to
pause something that's happening,
你可以说停停停一下就可以了
you can just say docker pause,
and that works.
当我想摆脱它的时候，当我想摆脱它的时候，
And then at the end of it, when I want
to get rid of it, docker kill, and
它不见了
it is gone.
让我们先杀了另一个，我不知道为什么它在跑。
Let's go ahead and kill that other one,
cuz I don't know why it's running.
> > 是否有要立即杀死他们的命令 ?
&gt;&gt; Is there a command to
kill all of them at once?
库兹我有很多人都跑了对我来说是不可知的
Cuz I have a lot of them running,
unbeknownst to me.
>> docker kill >> 它不起作用，我尝试过。
&gt;&gt; docker kill
&gt;&gt; It doesn't work, I tried.
>> 否，您必须执行 docker ps -q。
&gt;&gt; No, you have to do docker ps -q.
所以我觉得如果你这样做的话
So I think if you do, so
this subshells out to another shell,
好吧如果我把它放在美元符号的括号里
right, if I put it inside of
the dollar sign parentheses here.
然后我想你可能得检查一下我的位置
And then docker ps- q, I think -q, you
might need to check me on that one, and
我们再来一次吧
let's just do it again.
坚持住
Hold on.
我们会再跑几次
We'll run this a couple of times.
答案是，没有简单的方法可以做到。
The answer is,
there's no easy way to do it.
但我觉得你可以做码头工人
But I think you can do docker kill and
然后 docker ps -q。
then docker ps -q.
你可以看到它杀死了所有的人
And you can see there
it killed all of them.
因此 docker ps -q 仅输出标识或容器标识，对吗 ?
So docker ps -q just outputs the IDs or
the container IDs, right?
然后这就被送入了 Docker 杀死指令。
And then that's fed into
the docker kill command.
好吧另一个好的
Okay, another good one.
这是我需要你保持的大关键
So here's the big key
that I need you to keep.
当我看到码头和码头的时候它花了我一秒的时间
When I saw docker run and docker exec,
it took me a second to figure out,
为什么我需要这两个命令对吗
why do I need both of these commands,
right?
Docker 运行将启动新容器。
Docker run is going to
start a new container.
Docker exec 将在现有容器上运行某些内容，对吗 ?
Docker exec is going to run something
on an existing container, right?
有道理吗 所以当我说码头的时候
That make sense?
So when I say, docker run like this,
就会有一个新的宝莱坞容器了对吧
it's going to start up a new
hollywood container, right?
但如果我说 Docker exec 它会尝试
But if I say docker exec,
it's going to try and
找个容器来对付某些东西吧
find a container to execute
against something, right?
所以这个，我又跑了一个 Docker 容器。
So this one,
I ran another docker container.
所以如果我说 " docker ps " 你可以看到我有一个好莱坞的
So if I say docker ps, you can see here
I have this hollywood one running,
它叫弗文特 - 卡拉姆
it's called fervent_kalam.
我要对费文特 - 卡拉姆说
And I'm going to say docker
exec against fervent_kalam, or
我可以把身份证放在那里，这两个都可以工作。
I can put the ID there,
both of those will work.
我只想看看到底是怎么回事
And I just wanna see
what's running on that.
我可以说的是
So I can say ps aux.
你可以看到，它在运行一堆东西，对，
And you can see there,
it's running a bunch of stuff, right,
因为它有各种不同的宝莱坞容器
because it has all the various different
hollywood containers going on.
我们也可以说是吧
We can also say ls, right?
你可以看到在根目录下， pwd，它会给我一个斜杠，对吗 ?
You can see that's in the root directory,
pwd, it will give me a slash, right?
因此，这与正在执行的容器正在运行。
So this is running against that
ongoing executing container.
这有道理吗
Does that makes sense?
所以如果我想和它联系的话我只能说巴什
So if I wanted to connect to it,
I could just say bash.
我想我得说了
I have to say -it, I think.
现在，我实际上是连接到同一个正在运行的容器，对吗 ?
And now, I'm actually attached to
the same running container, right?
所以如果我说的是
So, again, if I say ps aux,
你可以看到这个集装箱的所有东西
you can see all the stuff that's
running against this container.
有道理吗
Make sense?
Docker 杀死了我们刚刚做的那个
Docker kill, that one that we just did.
我们走吧
Here we go.
好了我们要在这儿再做一个
All right, so
we're gonna do another one here.
这就是我们要做的 Docker 历史
This is what we're gonna do,
docker history.
我要说码头的历史
And I'm gonna say docker history, and
我们会说点冒号 12 号
we're gonna say node
colon 12 dash stretch.
在这里我们可以看到各种不同的
And here, we can see all of
the various different, and
我们马上就能在这里找到码头文件了
we'll get into docker files
here in just a second.
但我们可以看到历史上所有的变化。
But we can see all the changes
in the history here.
你可以看到，这是两星期前最后一次修改。
You can see,
this was last modified two weeks ago.
你可以看到各种大小和评论，以及图像和图像。
And you can see all the different sizes
and comments and created by, and images,
还有这类的东西
and all that kind of stuff.
这有点意思只是为了反省
This is kind of interesting
just to introspect how the,
您的 Docker 容器随时间推移而发生变化。
your docker container
is changing over time.
Docker 信息，如果您是
Docker info, this is useful like if you're
比如 SSHed 就像一个在云中运行的虚拟机
like SSHed into like a VM that's
out running in the cloud.
这将会转储一些关于主机计算机的信息
This will just dump a bunch of information
about the host computer that it's
啊，对吧 ?
on, right?
所以我可以看到这在 cgroupf 上是什么
So I can see that this
is on cgroupfs is what
它是用来控制的 cgroups
it's using for control, cgroups.
我可以看到这里有 20 个容器，都停了，对吧 ?
I can see that I have 20 containers here,
all of them are stopped, right?
这意味着我有一堆不必要的信息
Which means that I have a bunch of
unnecessary information sitting on my
计算机。
computer.
它不是在调试模式，我现在不是在运行群，像那样的一堆东西。
It's not in debug mode, I'm not running
swarm right now, bunch of stuff like that.
操作系统类型为 Linux，操作系统为 Docker Desktop。
OS type Linux,
operating system is Docker Desktop.
我在用社区引擎而不是企业的引擎对吧
And I'm using the community engine,
not the enterprise one, right?
就像这样，偶尔也会有一些有用的东西。
So just a bunch of stuff like that,
can be occasionally be useful.
好了我们做个码头管理公司
All right, so
let's do docker run -dit mongo,
这将会开始在后台运行 Mongo 。
this will start running
Mongo in the background.
现在我要说的是码头的顶部
And now I'm gonna say docker top that.
这和精确的 ux 是一样的吧
This is the same as doing
like exact px aux, right?
这只是一个简单的方法来查看所有
This is just an easy way to
see all the processes that
都在一个特定的容器里
are going on in a particular container.
这样做是有用的。
So that can be useful.
这个实际上，你可以看到它正在后台运行 mongodb ， mongod。
So this one is actually, you can see it's
running mongodb in the background, mongod.
博士会杀了他的
And docker kill that.
我们去码头看看码头破折号
Let's take a look at
docker ps dash dash all.
现在我，你可以看到，我有，我知道这个，
Now for me, you can see here,
that I have, I knew this,
我只留了 20 个容器对吧
I have 20 containers that
I've just kept around, right?
您可以看到此处的状态，因为所有这些都已退出，
And you can see the status here for
all these is exited,
因为我一直在执行容器，然后不删除它们。
because I keep executing containers and
then not deleting them.
这就是破折号的破折号
That's what that dash
dash rm is useful for.
这会给我留一堆空间但我一直忘了它
That would save me a bunch of space,
but I keep forgetting about it.
但是让我们看看其中一个，对吧。
But let's take a look at one of these,
right.
你可以看到其中的一些是 10 天前的。
So You can see some of
these are from 10 days ago.
这是我刚跑的那个蒙戈的
This one here that I just ran,
the mongo one.
我们来做码头工人的记录吧
Let's do docker logs from that.
你可以在这里看到，这是一堆 Mongo DB 的日志，对吧 ?
You can see here,
this is a bunch of Mongo DB logs, right?
这对任何人都不奇怪，对吧 ?
That should not be surprising to anyone,
right?
我运行了 Mongo DB ，生成了一堆日志。
I ran Mongo DB,
it generated a bunch of logs.
他们来了
So here they are.
这就是 docker 允许你做的事情。
So that's what docker allows you,
that can be ongoing.
还可以是还在跑的吧
It can be one that's still running, right?
它会跟踪你的信息
It'll keep track of that information for
you.
或者你可以看看最近关闭的那些
Or you can do look at ones
that have recently shut down.
但让我们说我想摆脱这一点我可以说
But let's say I want to get rid of that,
I can say docker rm that, and
它会去删除那个容器现在它释放了所有的空间
it will actually go and delete that
container, it now freed up all that space.
如果我想说我已经不再打算用蒙古人了
And if I wanted to, let's say I am no
longer planning on using the Mongo
我就可以说 Docker rmi ，就是把图像去掉，对吧 ?
container anymore, I could say docker rmi,
which is, remove the image, right?
蒙戈 现在我不会这么做了
Mongo.
Now I am not going to do that,
因为我们稍后会在这里用它
because we are going to use it
here later in the course, but
你也会释放其中的一些空间
that is how you would free up
some of that space as well.
还有码头我觉得是集装箱的修剪
And there is docker,
I think it's container prune.
这将除去所有已停止的容器，我想这样做。
This will remove all stopped containers,
I wanna do that.
我说了我回收了 422
And I say yes, and I reclaimed 422
我的 256 千兆字节计算机上的字节数。
bytes on my 256 gigabyte computer.
但现在如果我说 " docker ps " 什么都没有
But now if I say docker ps --all,
nothing there.
对吧 ? 所以把那些东西都扔掉了
Right?
So got rid of all that stuff.
再一次你可以做船坞的修剪机对吧
Now again,
you can do docker image prune, right?
这将释放大量的东西。
And that will free up
a substantial amount of stuff.
我现在不建议这样做
I don't suggest doing it right now.
>> 您知道在哪里可以看到所有图像吗 ?
&gt;&gt; You know where to see
like all the images?
>> 我想一个 Docker 映像列表。
&gt;&gt; I think a docker image list.
幸运的是
Lucky guess.
你可以看到我有不少
You can see I have quite a few.
有几个
Quite a few.
你可以看到它们，其中有些是相当大的。
And you can see they're,
some of these are quite big.
所以，嗯，我可能要把这个免费，我在这之后要做。
So, yeah, I probably need to go free this
up, which I will do after the course.
好了码头工人跑了
All right, so docker run -dit,
do 节点:12 - 拉伸。
do node:12-stretch.
所以现在我有了码头的位置，对，它是在后台运行的。
So now I have docker ps that, right,
it's running in the background.
我有个无聊的加加林我可以重新开始
I have boring gagarin,
I can do a docker restart, that.
毫不奇怪，这将重新启动容器。
Unsurprisingly, this will
restart the container.
就这样了
That's it.
在这个特殊情况下，为什么会这样呢 ?
In this particular case, so,
the reason why that probably took so
只要花那么长的时间
long, it might just take that long.
但很多时候这些容器都不会回复
But a lot of times some of these
containers won't respond to restart
信号，对。
signals, right.
这就是这些事情的工作方式。
So that's how these things work.
它会发出终止信号或发送重新启动信号。
It'll send like a terminate signal or
send a restart signal.
我认为，在这种情况下，节点不会响应于自身的重新启动信号。
I think in this case, node doesn't respond
to restart signals in and of itself.
所以它所做的是它等待十秒
So what it does,
is that it waits ten seconds,
就像好吧，你没重启，就硬把它给你重启了。
it's like okay, you're not restarting,
and it just hard restarts it for you.
因此，其中一些将会更快地出现，因为响应时间
So some of these will be a lot
faster because of the respond to
重新启动信号。
the restart signal.
但是，不管怎样，那是 Docker 重新启动。
But, Anyway, that's docker restart.
然后还有码头搜索
And then there's docker search.
假设我们想搜索一个 Python 容器
Let's say we wanna search for
a Python container.
我可以说 docker 搜索 python
I can say, docker search python.
你可以在这里看到它会从 Docker 集线器返家
And you can see here,
it'll return off of docker hub.
这里有一堆你可以使用的 Python 容器。
Here's a bunch of Python containers
that you could be using.
它会给你看星星，描述，所有这些东西。
It'll show you the stars,
the descriptions, all that kind of stuff.
那是码头搜查我很可能只是在码头上做
And that's docker search, I would
probably just do it on docker hub myself,
但如果您不喜欢浏览器，那么它在您的命令行中可用。
but it is available in your command
line if you don't like browsers.
可能是那些使用 Mosaic 来进行日常浏览的人。
Probably the same people that are using
Mosaic for their day-to-day browsing.